Podell, Bertram L.; Papers apap270
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bertram L. Podell Papers
1945-1970
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Podell, Bertram L. (Bertram Lawrence), 1925-
apap270
10.2 cubic ft.
The Bertram L. Podell Papers document Podell's service as a New York State Assemblymen and Congressmen from the mid-1950s through the early 1970s.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Bertram Podell initially donated his papers in a series of acquisitions to Syracuse University between 1967 and 1971. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Bertram L. Podell was born on December 7, 1925 in Brooklyn, New York. As a young adult he served in the United States Navy during World War II. After the War, he graduated from St. John’s University in 1947 and acquired a degree in law from Brooklyn Law School in 1950. He maintained a law practice throughout his life.
A Democrat, Podell became a member of the New York State Assembly representing Kings County in 1955 and served 14 years in the 170th through 177th New York State Legislatures. In 1968 constituents elected him to the U.S. House of Representatives in a special election for the 13th Congressional District (Brooklyn). He was re-elected to Congress three more times and served until 1975. Podell was an unsuccessful candidate for re-nomination by his party in 1974.
Toward the end of his Congressional career, Podell was indicted and ultimately plead guilty to bribery charges. He served several months in jail and then returned to his law firm where he spent the remainder of his years. Podell died of kidney failure at the age of 79 on August 25, 2005 in New York.
Scope and Contents
The Bertram L. Podell Papers document his work as a New York State Assemblyman and Congressmen during the years 1953-1970. The papers include legislative bills and files, newspapers, correspondence, resolutions, and various published materials. major topics in the subject files include conservation, education, highways, motor vehicles, labor, and gambling. A large portion of Podell's Assembly files discuss the Committee of Local Finance which he chaired for a period of time.
Overall the collection contains more material from Podell's tenure in the New York Assembly rather than the U.S. House of Representatives. Please note that the collection does not include records related to his final years in Congress, his trial or the later part of his life.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - General Subject Files, 1945-1968, Undated
Series 2 - Congressional Subject Files, 1963-1970, Undated
Series 3 - Bills and Resolutions, 1963-1967, Undated
The files in all three series are arranged alphabetically. Series 3 is arranged alphabetically by legislation type and then chronologically by bill number.
Politics and Politicians; Politicians--New York (State); Education, Higher--New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Correspondence; Legislative Records; Clippings (information artifacts); Files by subject; Podell, Bertram L. (Bertram Lawrence), 1925-; New York (State)--Legislature--Assembly; United States--Congress--House; Naval Applied Science Laboratory (Brooklyn, N.Y.)
- General Subject Files, 1945-1968; Undated; 1; 6.0 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains subject files from Bertram Podell's tenure in the New York State Assembly. The files cover a wide assortment of topics, including committee work, conservation, City University, education, New York State revenue, and gambling. Correspondence and news clippings are kept within the subject files.
  - Abortion, 1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 1-2)
  - Air Pollution, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1965 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Assembly Calendar of Bills, 1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Assigned Risk-Insurance Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Automation, 1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Balfour Declaration 50th Anniversary, 1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Banking, 1967; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Banking Bill Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Banks, 1964-1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Barnett, Philip, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Bartlett, Richard, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Beatnicks Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Billboards Press Releases, Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Birch, 1963; 1966; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Birch Society, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Birch Society Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Blue Cross, 1963-1965 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - B'nai B'rith, 1955-1956; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Board of Examiners Bill, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Bonds (NYC) Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Brownstein Bill on Beauty Salons, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Budget (Governor's), 1961; 1964-1965 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 25-27)
  - Budget Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Budget Statement, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Budgets for Select New York State Cities and Towns, 1964 (Flat-file 1)
  - Burns, John J., 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Campaign (Offers of Assistance), 1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Capital City News Bureau, 1966 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Capital Punishment, 1957; 1963-1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 33-35)
  - Capital Punishment Abolishment, 1963-1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 36-37)
  - Censorship, 1962-1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Certiorari, 1967 (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - City Club, 1965; Undated (Box 1 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - City Teachers Association, 1965 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - City University and State University, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - City University Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - City University Statement (Brooklyn College Rally), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - City University Statement (JLC Meeting on Higher Education), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Civil Liberties, 1956; 1964; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Civil Service Employees Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Commencement Address (New York Academy of Medicine), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Committee on Mortgages and Real Estate, 1950; 1960-1962; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Committee to Reduce Fire Hazards (Fireman Bill), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Condolence Letters, 1965 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Condon-Waldon Law, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Confessions Amendment Press Release, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Confessions Amendment Remarks, 1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Confessions Amendment Statements, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1954; 1965-1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Constitutional Convention Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Consumer Price Index, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Cornwall Project, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Corporation Laws, 1964; 1966-1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Cost of Living, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Cost of Living Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Crime Compensation Act, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Crime Rate (Growing), 1964 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Crisis (New York City), 1965 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Dairymen's League, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Democratic Legislative Program, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Democratic Program, 1964 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Divorce Law, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Education, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Education (Joint Legislative Committee), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Education (Public), 1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Election Law, Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Electronic Voting, Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Ellenbogen, Seymour, 1965 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Ethics, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Eulogies, 1963; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Favor File, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Feedback, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Finances (New York State), 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Finances (State), 1963-1965; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 42-43)
  - Fiscal Affairs (New York City), 1956; 1960; 1962-1964; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 44-46)
  - Fiscal Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Fiscal Reports (New York City), 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Fiscal Resources (Haller Plan), 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Fisher, Albert W., 1965; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Flatbush Democratic Club, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Flatbush Library Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Food Packaging and Marketing, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Form Letters, 1965; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Fox, J. Lewis, 1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Froehlich, David, 1964-1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Full Crew Law, 1964 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Gilbert, Hugh, Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Gimma, Joseph A., 1965-1966 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Goldwater and Flynn, 1965 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Governor's Releases, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Governor's Transportation Bond Issue, 1967; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Grundstein, Amrant S., Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Hanna, Edward A., 1966; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Harlem Cultural Center, 1967 (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Higher Education (Folder 1 of 2), 1957; 1960-1967; Undated (Box 2 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Higher Education (Folder 2 of 2), 1957; 1960-1967; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Statement (At Public Housing), 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Statement (City University Students), 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Highway Safety, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Hospitals, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Hospital Resolution Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Housing, Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Housing Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Hypnosis, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Income Pay (Correspondence), 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Infant Mortality (Correspondence), 1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Infant Mortality Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Integration (Schools), 1962-1964 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Investing in New York City Real Estate, 1953; 1963 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Investments (State), 1964; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Job Development Authority, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Joint Legislative Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on State Fiscal Policies, 1965 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Joint Legislative Committee to Study Revisions of Corporate Laws, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 21-23)
  - Judges Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Katzman, Barry, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Kerr-Mills Law, 1960; 1965 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Kisburg, Nicholas, 1965 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Leadership Fight, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Legislation (Misc. Correspondence), 1965 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 30-31)
  - Legislation (Misc. Correspondence), 1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 32-33)
  - Legislative Hearing, 1967; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Legislative Manuel Requests, 1967 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Legislative Memorandum, 1963-1965; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Legislative Reform, 1962; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Lexington School for the Deaf, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Liberal Party, 1965 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Libraries Press Releases (New York City), 1966; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Library Bill, 1967 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Lieberman, Mark, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Lindsay Administration Press Releases, 1966 (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Lindsay, John, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 3 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Lobbyists, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Lobbyists, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Lobbyists, 1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Local Finance (Marsh Public Health), 1966-1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Local Finance Committee, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Local Finance Law, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Local Finance Measures, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Local Finance Resolutions, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Local Finance Resolutions, 1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Local Government, 1959; 1965-1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Local Government, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 11-12)
  - Local Government Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Local Government Press Releases, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Local Government Statements, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Local Government Toronto, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Local School Boards, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Long Island University, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Lottery, 1964-1965; 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Luddy, William (Chairman of the Westchester Democratic Committee), 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Mangano-Ferrall Bill (Textbooks), 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Mattice, Frances J., Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Medicaid, 1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Medicare, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Medicare Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Memos to Members From B.L. Podell, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Message of Necessity Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Message of Necessity Statement, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Correspondence, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Press Releases, 1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Milk Control, 1960; 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Milk Program Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Minimum Wage, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Modlin, Vivian, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Morse, James, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Mortgage Leases Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Muraski, Gloria, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Narcotics, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Narcotics Press Releases, 1967; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Nash, Thomas (Chauffeur), 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - National Maritime Union of America, 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - New York Airways, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - New York State Job Development Authority, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Newsletters, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Nickerson, Eugene H., 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - No-Sock Bill, 1955; 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Noble, Paul (WNEW-TV Ch. 5), 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Nurses, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Nurses' Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Nurses' Salaries Press Releases, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Obscene Literature, 1963; 1965; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Off-Track Betting, 1959; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Off-Track Betting (In Favor of Off-Track Betting), 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Off-Track Betting (Oppose Off-Track Betting), 1965 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Orin Lehman, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Palestine Resolution, 1967 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Parker, John, 1966 (Box 4 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Past Legislative Sessions, 1956; 1958-1960; 1964-1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Penal Law and Criminal Law, 1965; 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Per Capita Aid, 1949-1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Personal (Podell), 1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Platform, 1962; 1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Podell and Podell, ESQS, 1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Prayers, 1965-1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Press Conference, Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Primary (State-Wide), 1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Programs and Platforms, 1965-1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Prospect Park Centennial Days, 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Public Health, 1964-1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Public Hearings, 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Publications (Official List), 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Racial Problems, 1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Racing Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Railroads, 1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Real Estate Mortgages, 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Real Estate Tax, 1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Reapportionment, 1960; 1964-1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Reapportionment, 1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Red Books and Manuals, 1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Regional Planning, 1965 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Religion and the Schools, 1955-1956; 1961; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Resolution 131: Local Finance Committee to Study Local Government, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Retail Merchants (Cliff Alanson), 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Rockefeller, 1964; 1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Rockefeller Railroad Improvements, 1968 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Rockefeller Resolution, 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Rosen, Richard M., 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Sabbath Bill, 1955; 1958-1959; 1962-1963; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Sabbatical Leave, 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Save the MET, 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Scholarship Letters, Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Scholarship Letters, Undated (Flat-file 2)
  - Scholarship Winners, 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Science Technology Foundation, 1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Sewage Bill, 1967; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Single Letting, 1945; 1965; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Single Letting, 1967 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Slums in the City (Press Releases), Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Speaker of the Assembly (Notices), 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Speeches, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - St. John's University, 1966 (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Staff-J.L.C., Undated (Box 5 (1-General Subject Files), Folder 46)